MARCOS SOUZA

Full Stack Developer

PERSONAL AFFIRMATION

Working with web development for over 5 years, graduated in Systems Analysis and Development.

Today I work as a Full Stack web developer using Docker, Php, Vue, Angular, Api rest, Mysql, Mariadb, Laravel, JavaScript, Azure, Git and others, applying Scrum and Kanban methodologies whenever possible in my workflow as well as the principles of S.O.L.I.D.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senai - National Industrial Learning Service | May 2023 - Mar 2024

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Using Angular, Laravel, Docker, Git, Azure, TypeScript Swagger and phpUnit, I worked as a Full Stack developer at Senai Alagoas, where I was mainly responsible for creating new features and maintaining the existing functionalities of the Sisbia and Siac systems, used for creation and application of evaluative test questions.
- During this journey, I contributed to restructuring and updating the versions of *Laravel* from v6 to v10, *Angular* from v6 to v10 and *Php* from v7.3 to v8.2.
- I was responsible for documenting the system's routes using swagger, as well as contributing to the creation of a checklist document to check the quality of the code and the application of the *S.O.L.I.D* principles during the code-review.

Slice - Money Operating Systems | jul 2022 - mar 2023

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Using Php, Vue.js, Quasar, Mariadb, GitLab and an internal Framework for Php, I worked as a Full Stack developer at slice, a startup in the financial sector. During this experience I had the opportunity to participate in the integration with banks such as Itaú and Bradesco through Api and import files for issuing bank slips and other services through our own platform.
- On this journey I was able to apply scalable methodologies, which allowed me a broader understanding of architecture in complex projects with large volumes of data.
- One of the main challenges was to create a transaction validator, similar to a two-step verification widely used today, in this challenge I used an SMS and Telegram messaging service to send messages in case of high value purchases, where after receiving a code and confirming the purchase would be approved or giving the possibility to deny and investigate further details about the purchase.

CONTACT

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/skymarkos7 Github: github.com/skymarkos7 Mail: marcosrealbmata@gmail.com phone/WhatsApp: (82) 99690-9200

GOAL

- Work together in the best way possible with the team I'm part of, sharing useful knowledge that helps with the organization or productivity of the company.
- I have experience with cross acting and I am open to new challenges and willing to learn new technologies that are necessary to overcome a challenge.

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Alagoas State University of Health Science - UNCISAL

TECHNOLOGIST IN SYSTEMS ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT | 2015 - 2019

- In addition to my training, I also completed a four-month internship at the university itself as I was chosen as one of the highlights of the 2018 classes. In this, using Python with Django, I contributed to the creation of an electronic form to record entries and exits from a university partner mortuary.

LANGUAGE

English - Advanced / Fluent

- ARTICULATION OF ORALITY. (11 MONTHS)
- INTERMEDIATE GRAMMAR (180 HOURS)
- BASIC GRAMMAR (180 HOURS)
 - CREDENTIAL CODE: 640F8B11-8394-4535-819C-A5B30A00C840

Portuguese - Native

Spanish - Intermediary

Vectis - Accounting Services | Nov 2022

FREELANCER | FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Using Vue.js, Google Maps Api and Telegram Api I had the opportunity to develop a portfolio from scratch for an accounting company. This portfolio included an alert mechanism for Telegram, informing strategic details, to enable future decisions such as: Which platform should a system be focused on, how many times a user searched for a service or even define a better location for the office.

Kino Auto Parts | Dec 2022

FREELANCER | FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Using *Vue.js*, *Google Maps Api* and *Telegram Api* and reusing a previous structure, I was able to develop a portfolio to demonstrate services for an auto parts company.

Fireman - Software Factory | May 2021

CHALLENGE | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- I developed this application as part of a challenge in a selection process. It was requested that using *Python*, 'philosophical phrases' be extracted from a given page using *web scraping*, extracting quotes and their authors, this data was stored in a *SQLite* database configured with the Django Framwork *API* and which in turn provided the data to a front in *Vue*.js where this information was shown in list form.

Lourenço Auto Parts | Aug 2020

FREELANCER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Using Php for the back-end, Html, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery for the front-end and Mysql with PhpMyAdmin to manage the database, as well as a dasboard layout purchased from a layout store. I developed a sales and inventory control system for an auto parts store.
- By working on this project, I was able to improve my skills in managing databases and sales systems. The project continued to receive growth and support until 2023.

Rede Comercializar - Association of Women Farmers in the city of Arapiraca | Jan 2016

FREELANCER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Using Php, Html, Css, vanilla JavaScript and Bootstrap, I led the development of a platform from scratch to expose and promote the products of 9 associations with more than 200 associated farmers. The platform, in addition to providing news and information related to the association, also enabled signaling the purchase of lots of a product through a form.
- While I was still improving in the technologies mentioned, I was responsible for coding, talking to the client and the hosting process. Throughout the process, I conducted periodic meetings to ensure the project's compliance with the client's needs. At the end of the project, the result was widely praised.

COURSE AND RECYCLING

Registered Scrum Basic™

- ID#RSB-6348372

S.O.L.I.D

- CODE: 19220974-09ea-409a-8601-75b6241b7db9

Docker

- CODE: 004dafbb-b663-4fb1-982b-4c8bfa106508

Swagger

- CODE: 2953bf8f-6d45-41e7-beba-b5b69b677761

Unit test

- CODE: 3909334-4y47-41e7-bybw-b5b69b008334